New adventure. Same wingman.
Carl's Date is a animation, family, comedy film directed by Bob Peterson.
Carl Fredricksen reluctantly agrees to go on a date with a lady
friend—but admittedly has no idea how dating works these days.
Ever the helpful friend, Dug steps in to calm Carl's pre-date jitters and offer
some tried-and-true tips for making friends—if you're a dog.
Carl (voice), played by Ed Asner.
Dug / Alpha (voice), played by Bob Peterson.
Carl's Date (also known as Dug Days: Carl's Date) is a 2023 American animated short film produced by
Pixar Animation Studios, written and directed by Bob Peterson and produced by Kim Collins.
It acts as the sixth and final episode of the miniseries Dug Days,
as well as the final entry in the Up franchise.
It stars the voice of Ed Asner, in his final acting role
before his death in 2021, and Peterson.
The short film follows Carl Fredricksen (Asner), who reluctantly goes on his first date
since his late wife Ellie's death, but has no idea how dating works.
Originally planned for release on Disney+, Carl's Date premiered in
theaters on June 16, 2023, along with Pixar's Elemental.
The film explores themes of date, love, dog, short film.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.